APURVA TIWARI

Data Analyst

Contact

Address

Indore, India 453771

Phone

06267843639

E-mail

apurvatiwari508@gmail.com

LinkedIn

http://www.linkedin.com/in/apurvatiwar i508

Skills

Databases: SQL Server, MySQL, Oracle DB, PL-SQL, Azure SQL, Azure Synapse Dedicated SQL Pool, Azure Synapse Serverless SQL Pool.

Azure Databricks, Azure Data Factory, Azure Data Lake, Azure Synapse Analytics.

Reporting Tools: Power BI.

OS: Windows/Linux

Integrating Tool/ ETL Tool: Azure Data Factory, Azure Synapse Analytics, Azure Databricks.

Languages

English Hindi

Data Analyst with 2+ years of experience. Working experience on Power BI, SQL, ADF, Azure Synapse Analytics and Data Lake. Knowledge on DAX functions, BI reporting, SDLC. Experience of pipeline creation in ADF and for ETL operations.

Work History

2024-05-Present

Statistical Production Service Architecture (SPSA)

Logikview Analytics, Indore- Data Analyst

Technologies: Azure Data Factory, Azure Databricks, Azure Data Lake

Azure SQL Database, Azure synapse Analytics, Power BI

· Handling POC part of the project

2023-03 -2023-01

Automated Data Analytics

Technofi India Pvt. Ltd, Indore- Data Analyst
Technologies: Azure Data Factory, Azure Databricks, Azure Data Lake
Azure SQL Database

- · Handled large Schemas and tables for integration
- \cdot Designed Pipeline job to extract data from BLOB storage and Http Connector
- · Worked with Azure Data Lake for loading data from source databases by creating linked services
- · Loading Data in azure data lake by Azure Databricks notebook and Dataflow Activities
- · Created Schemas and Table for Azure SQL Database to load data post ETL
- · Worked on MSSQL server for developing Stored Procedure
- · Developed Power BI dashboards for analysis by loading data from Azure SQL Database

2022-12 -2023-03

Stream Analytics

Technofi India Pvt. Ltd, Indore- Data Analyst

Technologies: ADF, Power BI Services

- · Setup Azure environment for stream analysis
- · Embedding Power BI Dashboard in a web application using azure stream analytics
- \cdot Created power bi dashboard for data visualization as per business requirements

2017-04 -2018-04

Easypay (End to End Solution for All Payments)

Axis Bank - Business System Analyst, Mumbai

Technologies: .NET, Oracle database

- · Analysis of production issues in perspective of system changes.
- \cdot Check for feasibility and solution to various requirements raised by product team.
- \cdot Communicate between functional as well as technical team for application integration and upgradation.
- \cdot Co-ordinate with developers and deliver the project as per schedule, conduct UAT, arrange business Sign-off and plan production movement.

Education

POST GRADUATE DIPLOMA: Diploma in Advanced Computing

CDAC ACTs - Pune

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING: Electronics And Communication Engineering

ACROPOLIS TECHNICAL CAMPUS - Indore